Sergey Kambalin

Senior Software Developer

kambalin@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sergeykambalin

Professional software developer with 10+ years of experience specializing in development of advanced web and mobile applications on TypeScript/JavaScript, as well as complex services and APIs on PHP/NodeJs. Always eager to grow and share my knowledge and professional experience with others. A good mentor and effective team leader.

Professional Experience _____

Evolution

Lead Frontend Engineer

July 2020 - present

• TBD

Senior Frontend Engineer

Nov 2019 - present

- Migrated a complex legacy project from JavaScript/AngularJS to TypeScript/React to align it with the company's technology stack
- Refactored the legacy project from monolithic to a modular structure to split the code ownership between sub-teams
- Developed an in-game chat module, using WebSockets for realtime communication. The module is used in all the company's games
- As a senior developer, was involved in interviewing, mentoring, and onboarding activities

Technology stack:

- TypeScript, JavaScript (ES6+)
- React & Redux ecosystem, Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Lerna + Yarn Workspaces, Jest, Enzyme, React/DOM Testing Library

IOLA

Senior Software Engineer/Architect

Oct 2018 - Nov 2019

- Architected, developed, and successfully released React Native iOS and Android applications
- Developed a PWA version of the application using React Native Web, reusing more than 90% codebase of the native versions
- Organized a Storybook driven development of UI components with visual regression testing using Jest and Puppeteer
- Developed micro-frontend UI Kit based on Web Components and Preact
- · Architected and developed a modular GraphQL server on PHP, supporting all major GraphQL features
- Implemented real-time GraphQL subscriptions on PHP using Server-Sent Events technology
- Achieved a significant performance increase of the GraphQL server by reducing the number of DB queries using Data Loader pattern
- Refactored the GraphQL server following Relay specification to let API consumers use Relay compatible libraries

Technology stack:

- TypeScript, React, React Native, React Native Web, Preact, Web Components, Babel, Webpack, Storybook, Jest, Puppeteer, Lerna
- PHP, SlimPHP, GraphQL-PHP, DataLoaderPHP, MySQL

Klika Tech LLC

Senior Software Engineer/Team Lead

Oct 2016 - Sep 2018

- Developed various company projects as a full-stack JavaScript/PHP developer, including SPAs, RESTful APIs, and services
- · Led a team of 3 members developing JavaScript SDK, which is used across multiple projects
- Achieved 100% test coverage of the JavaScript SDK using Mocha, Chai, and Sinon
- As a team leader, was involved in interviewing, mentoring, and onboarding activities
- Was the leader of the company's frontend community of more than 50 members

Technology stack:

- JavaScript (ES6+), React, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Mocha, Chai, Sinon
- PHP, PHPUnit, Pheanstalk, NodeJs, Sails, Express, MySQL

Skalfa Asia LLC

Senior Software Developer/Team Lead

Dec 2012 - Sep 2016

- Led architecting and development of a hybrid iOS/Android application based on Ionic Framework and SlimPHP
- Was a key developer in a team architecting and developing open source website platforms: Oxwall, Skadate
- · Led development of native iOS application on Objective C for the online dating platform: Skadate

Software Developer Jul 2010 - Dec 2012

• Took part in the development and optimization of a high load SaaS solution: Wall.fm

Junior Software Developer

Mar 2009 - Jul 2010

• Developed various PHP/JavaScript modules for Skadate online dating platforms, including core components and add-ons

Technical Skills

Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, GraphQL, MySQL

Frameworks React, React Native, Redux, Apollo GraphQL, GraphQL-PHP, Express **Tools** Webpack, Babel, Storybook, Lerna, NPM, Yarn, Composer, Docker

Tests Jest, Enzyme, React/DOM Testing Library, Puppeteer

Education

International University of Kyrgyzstan

Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Bachelor of Information Technology, Software Engineer

Sep 2003 - Jun 2007

Languages

- · Russian Native proficiency
- English Professional working proficiency